A new angle on the classic tale... And that's no lie!
The Adventures of Pinocchio is a family, fantasy,
adventure film directed by Steve Barron.
One of puppet-maker Geppetto's creations comes magically to life.
This puppet, Pinocchio, has one major desire and
that is to become a real boy someday.
In order to accomplish this goal he has to learn to act responsibly.
This film shows you the adventures on which he learns valuable lessons.
Geppetto, played by Martin Landau.
Pinocchio, played by Jonathan Taylor Thomas.
Leona, played by Geneviève Bujold.
Lorenzini, played by Udo Kier.
Felinet, played by Bebe Neuwirth.
Volpe, played by Rob Schneider.
The Adventures of Pinocchio is a 1996 fantasy film directed by Steve Barron and
based on the original 1883 novel of the same name by Carlo Collodi.
Barron collaborated with Sherry Mills, Tom Benedek
and Barry Berman on the screenplay.
It was a German, French, British and American venture produced by The
Kushner-Locke Company, Pangaea Holdings and Twin Continental Films.
It stars Martin Landau and Jonathan Taylor Thomas.
The film was a critical and commercial failure which led to the sequel, The
New Adventures of Pinocchio, being released straight to video.
The film explores themes of parent child
relationship, italy, love, school, boys.
The tone is emotional.